《女子监狱》
第二季第十一集
超级风暴旺达仍在加强
Super Storm Wanda is still gaining
正平稳地沿东海岸向上移动
force moving steadily up the Eastern Seaboard.
预计在其登陆前
Winds are expected to dissipate considerably
风力会大幅度减弱
before making landfall,
但这仍将是一场非常大的暴风雪
but this is still going to be a very large winter storm.
天啊  现在是不是每年都这样
Oh, hell. Is this every year now?
希望我的家人能安然度过
I hope my family's all right.
迈克尔和克里斯托会没事的
Michael and Crystal will be fine.
他们至少有栖身之处  想想可怜的吉米
They have a roof over their heads. Think about poor Jimmy.
是你自己要招揽这麻烦事
You're the one who's opening your door to this shit.
-别闹了  -喂
- Stop. - Hey, hey!
我们要求修好B区的厕所
Okay, so we want the B-Dorm bathroom repaired,
禁止用禁闭室当做惩罚的工具
restrictions on SHU as a punitive instrument,
还有无毒的洗衣粉
and non-toxic laundry detergent.
-还有别的吗  -有
- Anything else? - Yeah.
真正的枫糖浆  我讨厌现在的假货
Real maple syrup. I hate that fake-o kind.
-令人作呕  -老实说我更喜欢假货
- So nasty. - Actually, I like the fake kind better.
我们得好好讨论下这个问题
We're gonna have to discuss this more.
什么  不行
What? No!
快把这些要求交上去
Turn in the damn demands.
我们为了这事都折腾一周了
We've been working on this for a week already.
某人脾气暴躁哦
Somebody's cranky.
如果某人不是今早才加入抗议
Maybe if somebody hadn't just joined the strike this morning,
他们也会暴躁的
they'd be cranky, too.
抱歉
I'm sorry...
我以为这次活动中每个人的想法都是有效的
I thought this was a movement where everyone's ideas were valid.
不好意思
Excuse me!
你们的会议能去别的地方讨论吗
Will you take your powwow somewhere else?
我们想听电视节目呢
We're trying to hear the television.
我们还想带来积极的改变呢
Well, we're trying to effect positive change.
那你们能小声点吗
Can you please do it quietly?
我觉得这对你来说也很重要  修女
I'd think it would be important to you, too, Sister.
是啊  你进来的原因
Yeah, aren't you in here
不是把自己绑在核试验基地的一根旗杆上吗
'cause you chained yourself to a flagpole at a nuclear test site?
我进来是因为非法入侵核设施
It was for trespassing at a nuclear facility
再说了  那根旗杆是在美洲学校
and the flagpole was at the School for the Americas.
那些都已经过去了
And that's all behind me.
我现在老了  还有低血糖
I'm old. I have low blood sugar.
我希望监狱能给我机会
I was hoping that prison would give me a chance
让我有时间严肃地思考
to find the time for solemn contemplation.
是吗  思考什么
Yeah? Of what?
怎么当个孬种吗
Being a pussy?
珍妮修女  你要记得保持衣服干净熨烫平整
Sister Jane, you must remember to keep garments clean and ironed.
是的  修女
Yes, Sister.
-记得吃饭不要迟到  -不会的
- And don't be late for meals. - I won't.
还有吃饭的时候不要说话
And don't speak at meals.
尤其是不要跟简修女说话
And don't ever talk to Sister Jen.
为什么  她立下了静默的誓言吗
Why? Has she taken a vow?
不  她只是非常讨人厌
No, she's just terribly irritating.
你还有其他问题吗
Do you have any other questions?
是有一个问题
Well, I... I do have one.
还要多久耶稣才会跟我说话
How long before Jesus speaks to me?
你祷告的时候都没有跟耶稣说话吗
Do you not speak to Jesus in your prayers?
有  我有跟他说
Yes, I speak to him.
但目前为止  只是我在自言自语
It's been a one-sided conversation so far.
其他的修女总是在说
And the other sisters are always going on
耶稣跟她们说话了
about how Jesus speaks to them and...
还说他爱她们
tells them he loves them...
其他的修女喜欢吹嘘
The other sisters like to brag.
但耶稣只会临幸那些
But Christ only comes to those humble
对主忠诚的谦逊的人们
in their devotion to the lord.
不要把重点放在耶稣对你的付出
Focus not on what Christ may do for you...
而是在于你对耶稣的付出
but on what you can do for Christ.
好建议
Good tip.
谢谢  肯尼迪修女
Thank you, Sister Kennedy.
康斯坦茨修女
Constance.
明天华盛顿有游行  要求停止越南之战
Rally in Washington. Stop the war in Vietnam.
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
明天有游行
There's a rally tomorrow.
游行
A rally?
我想我们正式成为修女之前
I didn't even think we were allowed to read the newspaper
-都不允许看报纸吧  -没错
- until we take the veil. - Yes.
在康斯坦茨修女看见之前  赶紧扔掉
Put those away before Sister Constance sees you.
这事关紧要
This is important.
滥杀无辜的战争是违反上帝旨意的罪行
Indiscriminate war is a crime against God.
康斯坦茨修女也批准
Sister Constance gave her blessing for this.
是吗
She did?
那就行了
Oh, well, that's different.
"摇滚反强奸"
"Rock Against Rape"?
"强奸滚蛋"  "强奸投票"
"Rape and Roll"? "Rape the Vote"!
"强奸"一定要放在标题里  这样才能关联故事
"Rape" has to be in the title to connect it with the story.
某个地方的小音乐会
A small concert... somewhere.
对监狱有益的公关
Good PR for the prison.
对哦  监狱
Right, the prison.
这种不道德的性侵害
Mmm, this shameful sexual violation is
对你真是件好事啊  不是吗
really working out for you, isn't it?
我只是很高兴我们激发了一个话题
I am just happy that we have helped to start a dialogue.
我想谢谢你  乔
And I wanna thank you, Joe,
谢谢你协助我处理这件事
for your assistance in my handling of this.
你应该受到表扬
You deserve recognition.
何不用两到三百美元来表达你的谢意
How about a token of your appreciation in the $200 to $300 range?
那个就算了  但我为你准备了其他东西
In lieu of that, I have something else for you.
B区的厕所
B-Dorm bathroom.
你要修吗
You're fixing it?
找了一位许可名单上的承包商
With a contractor off the approved list.
-价格也很棒  -太好了
- We got a very good price. - That's great.
真是太好了
That's great.
-到底多少  -总之价格很好
- How much? - A very good price.
我还有好消息
And I have some more good news!
鉴于最近发生的事
In light of the recent events,
典狱长要送你新的防暴装备
the warden is sending you some new riot gear.
防暴装备
Riot gear?
那玩意怎么能防止强奸
How's that gonna prevent rape?
它不能防止强奸的发生
Well, it's not gonna prevent rape,
但如果有人被强奸了  从而引发起监狱动乱
but if somebody is raped and it incites a riot...
重型监狱搞了些新设备  所以旧的就给你了
We got some new gear in MAX and we're sending you the old stuff.
替我向典狱长说声谢谢
Just send the warden a thank you.
会的
I will.
对了
And... by the way,
如果你搞这个音乐会  需要乐队的话
if you end up doing this concert and you're looking for a band...
那个啊  我们已经找好了  谢谢了
Oh, yeah, we... we have that covered, but... but thank you.
明白
Got it.
抱歉这周的漫画不是很好笑
Sorry the comic's not very funny this week.
不会啊  我觉得很棒
Oh, no, I think it's great.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你这么说不会是因为同情我吧
You're not just saying that because you feel sorry for me
因为我算是个受害者
'cause I'm, like, a victim?
完全不是
No, not at all.
我觉得马儿对那只雕说的话非常勇敢
And I thought what the horse said to the eagle was very brave.
那是只鹰  不是雕
Oh, it's a hawk, not an eagle.
-是啊  -还是谢谢你
- Oh, yeah. - But... thanks.
查普曼  抱歉这个交晚了
Hey, Chapman, sorry I'm late with this.
这是什么
What is it?
放在简报上的抗议诉求
Our strike demands for the paper.
不行  算了吧
Oh, absolutely not. Forget it.
海利肯定不会同意的
It'll never get past Healy.
而且简报已经排好版了
Besides, the paper's already laid out.
三百字的关于斯科特・奥尼尔
I've got 300 words on Scott
对内战纪念品的喜爱的文章
O'Neill's love for Civil War memorabilia.
求你了
Please?
能不能至少试一下
Could you at least try?
好吧  我放进去
Fine... I'll put it in,
但我保证最后肯定会被扔进垃圾桶
but I guarantee you it's gonna end up in the trash.
谢谢你  查普曼
Thank you, Chapman.
你的善举会被历史铭记
History will remember you for this,
尽管我个人还是不太信任你
although I still don't trust you personally.
革命使陌生人成为同床之友
Revolution makes for strange bedfellows, huh?
不是说我们要同睡一床
Not like we're going to bed together...
布鲁克  你有听说甘地的名言吗
Brook, have you heard of the Gandhi quote,
"言之无益  就别开口"
"Speak only if it improves upon the silence"?
还真没听过
No... I haven't.
上下文是怎么样的  我爱甘地
What was the context? I love Gandhi.
他懂得如何反抗
That was a man who knew how to revolt.
你知道他出生和去世的那天都是周五吗
Did you know he was born and died on a Friday?
还有他的笔迹超级潦草
And also, he had really bad handwriting.
人们还说他和两个裸女同睡在他的床上  而不是
Also, they say he slept with two naked women in his bed not...
我能跟你说句话吗
Hey, can I... can I talk to you for a minute?
这是命令吗
Is that an order?
不是
No.
那不行
Then no.
我没空
I'm busy.
你回来工作啦
You're back at work.
那一跤摔得可真惨
That was a nasty fall you took.
别走  你要去哪里
Hold up now. Where you going?
我在跟你说话呢  站住
I'm trying to talk to you, stop.
我只想跟你说
All I'm trying to say to you
我可以给你点止痛药膏
is I can give you some Arnica for the pain.
你看起来很疼  我们是邻居
Look like you're hurt... and we're neighbors...
不止邻居这么简单
more than neighbors.
你住在我的房子里
You live at my house.
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
你是不小心被人抓回监狱
You come back to prison on accident
还是因为你在外面没人拿你当一回事
or 'cause outside you're too weak for anybody to take serious?
几个小毛孩觉得你是个大人物
What, you got some kids think you hot shit?
了不起嘛
Big deal.
你就像个恋童癖者  只不过不上床
You're like a pedophile without the sex.
我敢说那些真正的大人物会当面嘲笑你
Bet the real players laugh in your face.
可能还会免费操你
Probably fuck you for free, too.
你想把这件事搞得多糟
How much worse do you want this to get?
那就看你的本事了
How much worse you got?
放马过来吧
Bring it.
我没什么可顾忌的
What do I got left to lose?
查普曼  进来吧
Chapman, come in.
-你把简报带来了吗  -是的
- You got the paper? - Yes, I do.
很好
Good.
-你把广告加进去了吗  -是的
- You put the ad in? - Yes.
就在这里
It's right here.
安全地带
绝食抗议诉求
有一些女孩不太懂你广告的内容
You know, some of the other girls aren't sure what you're advertising.
"安全地带"  听起来像幼儿乐园
"Safe Place." It sounds like a preschool playgroup.
我必须得委婉点
Well, I had to be subtle.
"治疗"这个词会吓着人们
The word "Therapy" scares people.
但如果你让人们参与创造性的游戏
But if you engage people in creative play,
他们会更乐意分享自己的烦恼
they're more interested in opening up about what's troubling them.
看来你有阅读这方面的书籍
Sounds like you've been reading up.
要应用社会科学就必须多读书
You have to with the social sciences.
理论是不断发展的
The theories are constantly evolving.
这是件好事  否则我们情绪失控时
It's a good thing, otherwise we'd all still
仍会被迫接受电击疗法
be getting electroshock therapy for hysteria.
我母亲就被电击过
My mother had that.
老实说  还蛮管用的
It's pretty effective, actually.
在那之后  她总是做汤
She made a lot of soups after.
总而言之  先把这个印出来
Well... anyway... here, let's get this out.
唐纳森
Donaldson!
来了
Yeah.
拿这个去办公室  给我复印100份
Go down to the office and make me 100 copies of this.
-好的  -谢谢
- All right. - Thank you.
趁还没走  我有一事相求
While I'm here, I'd like to ask you something.
慢着  慢着
Hold on. Hold on.
拿着这张纸
I want you to take this piece of paper.
还有这根铅笔
I want you to take this pencil.
我想让你写下你现在的情绪
I want you to write down a feeling
并放进这个情绪罐
and put it in the Feelings Jar.
-为什么  -你晚点在安全地带就会知道
- Why? - You'll see later in Safe Place.
我很忙  但有空我肯定会去
I'm very busy, but I'll be there if I can.
把你的情绪写下来  查普曼
Write down the feeling, Chapman.
好吧
All right.
你能先把这个签了吗
Would you mind signing off on this?
我想在我的通话名单里增加一个人
I'd like to add someone to my call list.
艾丽克斯・沃斯
Alex Vause?
这不是什么拉拉之情
It's not a lesbian thing.
可你觉得这是个好主意吗
Still, you think this is a good idea?
不是  但她一直写信给我
No, but she keeps writing me letters,
我觉得这样有助于我们了断
and I think that it would help to give us some closure...
虽然从心理上来说  这是有用的
which is psychologically not without value.
谢谢你  海利先生
Thank you, Mr. Healy.
把你的心情告诉情绪罐
Tell it to the Feelings Jar.
感激
这是个好词
That's a great word.
为什么  费里达  你为什么要这样做
So what was it, Frieda? Why did you do it, huh?
是不是因为我没让你种大麻
Is it because I didn't let you grow pot?
还是因为我给你的西红柿浇太多水
Because I over-watered your tomatoes?
你为什么要出卖我
What did it take to sell me out?
红妈  我不知道你在说什么
Red, I don't know what you're talking about.
-我给你搞来纤维补充剂  -红妈  别这样
- I give you fiber supplements! - Red, come on.
我给还给你止痛膏
I give you BENGAY!
-而你就是这样报答我吗  -红妈  住手
- And this is how you repay me? - Red! Hey, hey!
我真不知道她在说什么
I don't know what she's talkin' about.
该死的
Fuck.
红妈  别这样  你刚跟家人团聚
Red, come on, you just got your family back.
你想乱指责人  把一切搞砸吗
You wanna mess things up making crazy accusations?
我知道是她  她就是叛徒犹大
I know it's her. She's the Judas.
那你就是被犹大出卖的耶稣咯
Oh, and you're Jesus, huh?
拜托
Come on.
你难说是她还是诺尔玛说的
You don't know she talked any more than Norma did.
诺尔玛
Norma.
好吧  你绝对是在多疑
All right... now I know you're paranoid.
听着  或许维只是根据事实作出推断
Look... all right, maybe Vee just put two and two together.
这又不算是
You know, we're not talking about
什么一等一的秘密  对吧
Batcave-level secrecy here, right?
是啊  说得好
Yeah, word.
而且你们又不是
And it's not like
没在公众场所用正常音量说过这事
you don't talk about this shit in normal volume in public places.
蠢货
Dummies.
你的厕所不在这
This isn't your bathroom.
老娘想去哪里拉屎就去哪里
I can take a shit where the fuck I want.
他们给黑人那边的厕所找了承包商
And... they got contractors on the black side.
终于要翻新了
Finally getting renovated.
天啊  日子蒸蒸日上啊
Hell! Moving on up!
你难道没有良心吗
Don't you have a conscience?
居然把毒品带来这里
Bringing drugs into this place?
你难道忘了崔希娅的遭遇吗
Don't you remember what happened to Tricia?
没忘
Yeah.
我也记得阿拉莫战役
I remember the Alamo, too,
1836年  美国德克萨斯州寻求独立与墨西哥发生的战争
但我还是照样继续吃墨西哥食物
but that don't keep me from eating Mexican food.
在监狱里毒品不是最罪大恶极的东西
And drugs in the prison ain't the craziest thing to ever happen.
不过我会告诉你什么才是
I'll tell you what is, though.
你觉得你可以开一条路
You thinking you can open a road...
上面只让白人通行
and say only white people can drive on it.
这是美国
This America.
厕所可能被划分隔离
The bathrooms may be segregated...
但市场是自由的
but the market be free.
对了  的确有人把你出卖了
Oh, but, uh... FYI, somebody did rat you out.
那人是大波  走啦
It was Boo. Puff out.
这个谜团解开得真快
Well... that was a short mystery.
警棍  头盔和盾牌
We got billy clubs and helmets and shields.
天啊  这些东西太棒了
Man, this stuff is great.
是啊  但愿我们不需要用到
Yeah, hopefully, we never have to use it.
太好了  天啊
Great, great. Oh, my God!
那是催泪弹吗
Is that tear gas?
-什么  我看看  -别抢  小心点
- What? Let me see that. - Hey! Take it easy. Careful!
盘点一下就把这堆东西锁进军械库里
Just take an inventory and lock this stuff up in the armory.
军械库
Armory?
放武器的地方
Weapons holding.
-那个大壁橱  -对哦
- The big closet! - Oh, yeah.
奥尼尔  快看  你出名了
Hey, O'Neill! Look, you're famous.
我看看
Hey, let me see that.
你应该用我帮你拍的那张照片
You should've used that other picture I took of you.
好啦好啦  把嘴闭上
Okay, okay. Shush your mush.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
绝食抗议
Hunger strike?
对啊  你不知道这件事吗
Oh, yeah, you didn't know about that?
不  我完全不知道
No... I didn't fucking know about that.
你们知道什么是人类扩音器吗
Okay, do you guys know the human megaphone?
不知道  是什么
No, what is it?
就像占领华尔街用的手势那样
It's like the Occupy hand signals.
把手指向上动表示"好"
So, what we do is up twinkles for "Yay."
-就是"是"的意思  -动手指
- That means "Yes." - Twinkle!
手指朝下动是"不"
Down twinkles for "Nay."
得了吧  我们不需要用手语
For God's sake, we don't need hand signals.
我们只有四个人
There's only four of us.
目前只有四个  以后就不止啦
Now. Thinkin' of the future.
举拳  这是"反对"的意思  举拳
Okay, fist up... fist up for "Oppose." Fist up.
意思是"我有疑问"
This means, "I have a question."
够了  头儿是谁
All right, who's the leader?
我们现在群龙无首
We are a leaderless movement,
也可以说是人人都是头儿
or rather... leader-full.
-看来你是头儿  -我不是
- Let's just say it's you. - Uh, I'd rather not.
我看到你们的要求了  有点不明白
I read your demands. They're a little confusing.
的确还需要完善
Well, it's a work-in-progress.
你们要求修好B区的厕所
Well, you say you want the B-Dorm bathroom fixed.
没问题
Done.
-我们成功了  -太好了
- We did it! Yay! - Yay!
不关你们的事  厕所早就决定要修了
You didn't do anything. It was already happening.
你们要求限制使用禁闭室
You say you want restrictions on the use of the SHU.
这个要求到底是什么意思
What does that mean, exactly?
监狱没有问责制
There's no accountability.
任何囚犯在任何时间
People get thrown in for no reason...
会被无缘无故扔进去
for any period of time, arbitrarily.
沃森几乎每隔一个月就被扔进去
Watson's been in there, like, every other month.
那是她自找的
She brought that on herself.
至于她待在里面的时间
As far as the duration of her stay,
禁闭室自有一套系统和严格的指导方针
there is a system in place with strict guidelines,
我们没有义务向你们说明它的运作方式
and we are under no obligation to explain to you how it works.
不过恰巧  你的朋友沃森今天可以出来了
But as it so happens, your friend, Watson, is coming out today.
-太棒了  -恭喜你  瑜伽
- Yes! - Congratulations, Yoga!
这也是巧合  完全跟你们无关
Again, just a coincidence. Nothing to do with this.
还有其他的吗
Is there anything else?
有个关于枫糖浆的问题
There is a maple syrup situation.
有需要我重视的吗
Anything I can take seriously?
我有一个问题
I have an issue.
你打算怎么处理
What are you going to do
监狱里对老年人的照料问题
about the quality of senior care in this prison?
这个好  修女  但我们还没投票呢
Excellent issue, Sister, but we haven't voted on that yet.
或许我们可以先记下来  晚点再谈
Maybe we could put a pin in it, talk about it later?
老年人是监狱里增长最快的人口
The elderly are the fastest growing population in prison
她们有特殊的需求
and they have special needs.
用所谓的"提前释放"来替代照料
So-called "Compassionate release" in lieu of care
完全不能让人接受
is completely unacceptable.
你不能把生病的老人扔到大街上
You can't dump sick old ladies on the street.
这丧尽天良  毫无人道而是违法的
It's unconscionable, inhumane and... illegal.
你必须履行你的义务
You must meet your obligations.
事态变严重了
This just got real.
因为我叫你孬种  所以你才这么有种  对吧
It's 'cause I called you a pussy, isn't it?
我是为了吉米
It's for Jimmy.
就是因为我叫她孬种
'Cause I called her a pussy.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你确定我们不用付油钱吗
Are you sure we can't offer you money for gas?
就当我捐给你们所谓的教堂了吧
Just consider it a donation to your so-called church.
-再见  -再见
- Bye! - Bye!
那真是太棒了  真的
That was wonderful, truly.
真难以置信  谢谢你带我去
It was incredible! Thank you so much for bringing me.
我当初还担心当修女会很无聊
I was afraid nunning was going to be boring,
但刚才真是太激动了
but that was so exciting.
修女们  你们去哪儿了
Sisters, where have you been?
我们去参加游行了
We were at the rally.
康斯坦茨修女叫你们立刻去见她
Sister Constance would like to see you immediately.
我们不会是有麻烦了吧
We aren't in trouble, are we?
你明明告诉我们  修女批准了啊
You told us we had Sister's permission.
-精神上批准了  -什么
- In spirit. - What?
"你当开口按公义判断
"Open your mouths, judge righteously,
为困苦和穷乏的辨屈"
defend the rights of the poor and needy."
箴言第31章第9条
Proverbs 31:9.
你欺骗了我们
You duped us.
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
自己变成了坏修女
I fell in with the bad nuns.
大不了罚我们忏悔
So, we'll do some penance.
反正我们整天都在忏悔
We do penance all day anyway.
至少现在是为我们引以为傲的事情
At least now it can be for something we're proud of.
意义在哪里
I mean, what is the point?
就为了总是低头  保持刻板形象吗
To keep our heads down and be well starched?
我们没有工作  没有丈夫
We have no jobs... no husbands.
如果我们不努力让世界变得更美好  那谁会这么做
If we don't fight to make the world a better place, who will?
猪吗
The pigs?
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
感觉的确很好
It did feel good.
我听说你在禁闭室有一间是专门留给你的
So, I heard they got a special cell for you in Seg.
门外还有块小牌
Got a plaque outside the door
写着"沃森专用"
that say, "Reserved for Watson."
把你的臭嘴闭上
Shut the fuck up!
你根本不知道那里是什么样
You got no idea what it's like,
所以别他妈假装好像你知道一样
so don't even fucking act like you fucking know.
别紧张  放松  姑娘
Take it easy now. Easy, girl.
现在没事了  你回家了
You all right, now. You all right. You're home now.
我陪着你呢
I got you.
我会照顾你的  坐下吧
I'm gonna take care of you now. Sit down.
我也会
Me, too.
各位麻烦听我说
Can I get everybody's attention, please?
这是安全地带最后一次报名
This here is the last call for Safe Place sign-up.
我重复一遍  这是安全地带最后一次报名
I repeat, it is the last call for Safe Place sign-up.
安全地带是什么玩意
What the fuck is Safe Place?
海利新发明的玩意
It's Healy's new thing.
就好像那种怂恿学生相互告密的学校
It's like some kind of... snitching school.
你去参加  对别人大声抱怨
You go and sound off on people...
然后他就私下取消你一次记过
and he gives you a shot off your record.
真的吗
Serious?
千真万确  我不骗你
Word, I don't lie.
他的办公室里还有个告密罐
He even got a snitching jar in his office.
你们好啊
Hey, y'all.
想报名参加安全地带吗
Wanna sign up for Safe Place?
我们不感兴趣
We're not interested.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
光头黑妹可是报名了哦
Bald blacky signed up.
不报
Nah.
你要我报名吗
You want me to sign up?
我可以监视她  就像间谍眼
I could keep an eye on her, like a... like an eye-spyer.
对  你是可以
Yeah, baby, you do that.
-安全地带  谢谢  -这个想法不错
- Safe Place! Thank you. - That is some good thinking.
-我会永远为你着想  -你们好啊
- My brain will always be there for you. - Hey, y'all.
好让你不必操劳
Thinking things... so you don't have to.
安全地带报名  最后一次机会  有人报吗
Safe Place sign-up, last call over here, anyone?
宾州白妞
Hey, Pennsabama!
等我
Wait up.
我知道什么样的广播故事很精彩
I know what makes a great radio story.
阿拉斯加是一个有趣的地方
Alaska's an interesting place.
如果我认为没人想听
I wouldn't have gone there
我就不会到那里去了
if I thought nobody wanted to hear about it.
皮特  你能过来坐下吗
Pete, can you come sit down?
但我还在发泄怒气呢
But I'm still venting!
我们有话想对你说
We wanna talk to you about something.
感觉有诈
I sense an ambush here.
过来坐
Come sit.
我不是酒鬼
I'm not an alcoholic.
我是澳洲人
I'm Australian.
坐下
Sit down.
我们不在乎你是否喝酒
We don't care if you drink.
好的
Okay, so...
你不在的时候  我和莱瑞经常在一起
while you were away, Larry and I spent a lot of time together.
我知道  然后呢
Right. And?
然后
And...
我们变得亲密
we became close.
比以前更亲密
Closer than before.
好吧
Okay.
这真尴尬
This is awkward.
不  伙计
No, mate.
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're gonna say.
-是吗  -是的
- You do? - Yeah.
我又不是傻瓜
I'm not an idiot.
你们觉得我会不知道你们的小秘密吗
You think I don't know what's going on here?
这完全是意外
It's nothing we ever planned.
当然是
Of course not.
一切都合情合理
I mean, it all makes sense.
你  波丽
You... Polly...
还有我
and me.
还有你
And you?
对啊  我们都是朋友嘛
Why not? We're all friends.
不  皮特  我们不是要玩3P
No, Pete, this isn't about having a threesome.
不是吗  我理解错了
No? My bad.
那是什么
What is it?
我要离开你
I'm leaving you.
为了他吗
Uh, for him?
我们没有开始很久
It hasn't been going on long.
你
You...
让我戴绿帽了
cuckolded me?
我从没这么想过
I never thought of it that way.
你
You...
趁我不在的时候上了我老婆
fucked my wife without me being there, too.
你让我戴绿帽了
You cuckolded me!
皮特  我们就实话实说吧
Pete, let's admit something.
我一有孩子  你就跑了
The moment I had the baby, you bailed.
你没准备好像成年人那样负起责任
You're not ready to be a grown-up.
所以小三就准备好了吗
And rebound boy is?
莱瑞出现了
Larry fucking shows up.
你觉得这对我很容易吗
Look, you think this is easy?
我要结束一段婚姻  他要结束一段感情
I'm ending a marriage, he's ending a relationship,
我上了我最好朋友的未婚夫
I fucked my best friend's fiance.
但这是真的
But it's real.
我觉得我们的相爱
And... I think it's the best thing
是发生在我们身上最棒的事情
that's ever happened to both of us.
我之所以离开
I went away...
是想为我们儿子成材
so I could be somebody for our son.
拜托  皮特
Come on, Pete...
你知道这不是真的  你离开是因为
you know that's not true. You went away because...
妈的
Shit!
用不着你来告诉我
Don't tell me what I know.
-皮特  -该死的
- Pete! - Fuck!
该死的
Oh, fuck!
-天啊  -妈的
- Oh. Oh, my God. - Shit.
你有空吗
You got a minute?
干嘛  你找不到你其他妈妈了吗
What, you can't find your other mommy nowhere?
开玩笑啦
Kidding.
怎么了
What?
那破事发生后  你应该飘飘然啊
You should be walking on air, the way this shit turned out.
什么破事
The way what shit turned out?
-有人因为我要坐牢了  -话是没错
- There's a dude going to jail because of me. - Yeah...
但至少你和小矮子可以一瘸一拐朝着夕阳奔去
but at least you and Stumpy get to limp off into the sunset.
我现在都不愿看他
I can't even fucking look at him.
而且大家都知道我怀孕了
And now everybody knows I'm pregnant.
这样下去可不行
That is never gonna work.
我真是太笨了
I'm so fucking stupid.
没关系
Hey, it's all right.
没事的
It's all right.
很多人都笨
A lot of people are stupid
但还是生活还是过得很充实多彩
and still live full, productive lives.
至少你知道你有钱拿
At least you know you're getting paid.
有钱拿
Paid?
天啊  姑娘  我难道什么都没教过你吗
Oh, Jesus, girl, didn't I teach you nothing?
你被狱卒强奸了  你可以告政府
You get raped by a guard, you get to sue the government.
更棒的是  你怀孕了
Plus, even better, you got a baby...
这就意味着曼多萨会给你抚养费
which means child support from Mendez
你还可以勒索瘸子给钱
and extortion money from Gimpy.
我跟你说  这次强奸
I'm telling you, this rape...
是这辈子发生在你身上最棒的事情
is the best thing that ever happened to you.
那些贱货在背后说你的唯一原因就是出于嫉妒
The only reason them bitches is talking is because they jealous.
可是宝宝出生后没有爸爸怎么办
And then what happens when the baby ends up with no daddy?
又是一个生长贫民窟的娃
Another fucking barrio baby.
别那样想
You don't think about that.
你当初也不是在非传统的环境中长大的
You was raised in a non-traditional setting...
你现在不也好好的吗
and you turned out great.
谢谢你安慰我
Thanks, Ma.
别客气
Sure, no problem.
等有钱的时候  别忘了我就行
Just remember me when them checks start comin' in.
利奇菲尔德联邦监狱的一个犯人
An inmate from Litchfield Federal Prison
给你打来电话
is attempting to contact you.
接听请按1
To accept this call, please press one.
你在信中声称
So, in your letter,
你曾试图为我争取跟你一样的协议
you claim you tried to ask if I could get the same deal you got,
但你却没有解释为什么
but what you failed to explain is why
我按照你教的一字一句陈述证词
after you coached me in exactly what to say in my testimony,
你却说了跟我完全相反的话
you suddenly do an about-face and say the exact opposite thing.
你是想听长点的解释还是短点的
You want the long version or the short version?
短的吧  你只有一分钟
I want the short version. You have one minute.
就这样吗
It's like that, huh?
不  我的电话卡快没钱了
No, my... phone credit is running low.
帕波  我当时获刑的时间比你还长
Look, Piper... I was facing more time than you.
我律师跟我说  我的证词可以将库巴关进监狱
My lawyer told me that my testimony would put Kubra away...
一定可以
for sure...
还说我当天就可以获释
and that I could walk that same day.
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
你的律师比莱瑞的爸爸强多了
Your lawyer is a better lawyer than Larry's dad.
才不是
No, he isn't.
他错了  库巴无罪释放了
He was wrong. Kubra walked.
什么
What?
法庭宣布审判无效
There was a mistrial.
某个混蛋弄丢了证物
Some dumb fuck mishandled the evidence.
他被放出来了
He's out.
所以只有我被关进监狱吗
So I'm the only one who went to prison?
我告诉你在我指证库巴后  他没被关起来
I tell you that Kubra's free after I testify against him
而你却只关心这个吗
and that's all you have to say?
警察会保护你的  对吧
Well, I mean, they're protecting you, right?
是啊  他们会保护我
Yeah... they're protecting me.
昼夜不停地监视我
There's around-the-clock surveillance.
我的意思是
And by that, I mean...
我每周只见我的缓刑假释官20分钟
I see my probation officer every week for about 20 minutes.
天啊
Oh, my God.
艾丽克斯
Alex...
艾丽克斯  你是说真的吗
Alex, are you serious?
-你现在在哪里  -皇后区
- Where are you right now? - Queens.
你在皇后区
You're in Queens?
我才去过那儿
I was just there!
什么
What?
算了  我现在不能跟你说这个
Never mind. I can't get into that right now.
艾丽克斯  你不应该待在纽约
Alex, you shouldn't be in New York.
艾丽克斯  你应该去内华达
Alex, you should be in fucking Nevada or...
或阿根廷  或别的地方
or Argentina or something.
没事的
That's fine.
托马斯・品钦在纽约藏了很多年
Thomas Pynchon hid in New York for years.
皇后区也没那么糟糕  没人会来看我  但
And Queens isn't that bad. No one comes to visit, but...
这里的希腊食物很好吃
it has pretty good Greek food.
再说了  我不能离开本州
Besides, I'm not allowed to leave the fucking state.
那是我获释的条件之一
It's part of my release.
本次通话还剩30秒
You have 30 seconds remaining for this call.
该死的
Oh, shit!
你在打给我之前  就不能多充点钱吗
You couldn't have added more credit before calling me?
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我之前又不知道
Well, I didn't plan ahead.
我得当面跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you in person.
你能把我加进你的探监表里吗
Can you get me on your visitation list?
我试试  但艾丽克斯
Well, I'll try, but, Alex,
你确定你现在真的安全吗
are you sure... are you sure that you're safe?
是的  我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
快把我弄进探监表  这样我们就可以好好谈了
Just... get me on your list and we can talk about it then.
好的
Okay.
靠  去你妈的
Fuck! Motherfucker!
30秒这么短吗
You call that 30 seconds?
喂  这可是联邦财产
Hey, that's federal property...
狗屁联邦财产
You're federal property!
对不起  对不起  真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
生理期  我只是生理期暴躁
Menses, it's menses madness.
快走吧
Ew, just go.
快开门
Come on, open up.
我知道你在里面  我看见你进去了
I know you're in there. I saw you go in.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
你知道我想怎么样
You know what I want.
我想让你把可回收的垃圾分类
I want you to separate your damn recyclables.
你不能一直把纸箱扔在外面
And you can't keep leaving cardboard boxes outside.
你得先把它们压扁
You need to break 'em down first.
我看见你了
I see you!
-干嘛  -你不是吴太太
- What? - Oh, you're not Mrs. Woo.
我不是  我是艾丽克斯
No, I'm not Mrs. Woo. I'm Alex.
我是杰
Hey, I'm Jay. I, uh...
我是收垃圾的
I deal with the garbage.
纸箱的事很抱歉  下次我会先压扁
I'm sorry about the boxes. I'll break them down next time.
我的要求就这么多
That's all I ask.
-欢迎入住这栋楼  -多谢
- Welcome to the building. - Yeah.
艾丽克斯  你是艾丽克斯・沃斯吗
Oh, Alex! Alex Vause?
又怎么了
What?
有几个阿拉伯人在找你
Some Arab guys were looking for you.
可能不是阿拉伯人  但
Maybe not Arab, but you know...
是深肤色的男人
dusky gentlemen.
你是对的
Well, you're right.
幸好你把捕鲸矛藏起来了
It was good you hid the Aleut whaling spear.
-抱歉  -不
- Sorry. - No...
我很高兴我跟你一起告诉他
I'm glad I was here to tell him with you.
在这种情况下  这样做才是对
I mean... it was the right thing to do under the circumstances.
老实说  皮特私底下肯定高兴得跳脚
Honestly, Pete is secretly jumping up and down with joy
终于脱离苦海了
to be let off the hook.
他只是要证明自己的男子气概
He just needed to affirm his manhood.
或许他可以和帕波上床  我们就扯平了
Maybe he can fuck Piper and we'll have reciprocity.
老实说  我和帕波
Well, Piper and I actually...
是和平分手
actually ended in a good place.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我还得跟她解决些问题  但
I still need to work some shit out with her, but...
我很高兴你们没事
I'm glad you two are good.
那就这样了
So that's it, huh?
帕波知道了
Piper knows...
皮特也知道了
Pete knows.
我们真在一起了
We're doing this.
你还是可以离开
You can still leave.
离开  我为什么要离开
Leave? Why would I leave?
可能是因为我不知道这段感情对你有什么好处
I guess I don't know what you get out of this relationship.
我很害怕  因为
And I'm scared, because...
当你试图艰苦跋涉穿越冰原  会发生什么
what happens when you wanna... trek across an ice field?
我可以保证
I can guarantee you...
我永远也不会想艰苦跋涉穿越冰原
that I will never wanna trek across an ice field.
我知道
I know.
你没这样的体力
You're so not rugged.
这么说可不对
That is not true.
我有次参加过以色列军队夏令营
I once did Israeli Army summer camp.
我在沙漠里跟一名叫舒姆里克的指挥官开乌兹枪
I shot Uzis in a desert with a commander named Shmulik,
所以我有这样的体力
so I can do rugged.
我只是受不了冷气候
It's the cold I don't like.
笨蛋
Idiot.
你是我人生中唯一一个
You know, you're the only person I've ever met
叫我笨蛋
who can call me an idiot...
却不会让我真的觉得自己笨的人
without actually making me feel like one.
或许我的音调不对
Maybe I'm using the wrong inflection.
我们都会有情绪
We all have feelings...
有些我们的情绪太过于强烈
and some feelings that we feel are so strong
很难让我们去做
that it's hard for us to be the person
心里真正想成为的那个人
that we know in our hearts that we can be.
所以我们处理这些
So what's the best way for us
强烈又危险的情绪的最好方式是什么
to deal with these kinds of powerful and dangerous feelings?
让它们好看
Let 'em have it.
不  是去谈论
No... talk about them.
如果我们敢于谈论自己的问题
If we talk about our problems,
这会让我们更容易处理自己的情绪
it makes it easier for us to process our feelings
同时也让我们知道自己并不孤单
and it helps us to realize that we're not alone.
今天谁想第一个来分享
Who'd like to start the sharing for today?
我
Oh, me.
等下
Hold on.
我们从弗洛雷斯开始好了
Hey, let's... let's start with Flores.
-我吗  -是的
- Me? - Yeah.
这是一根发言棒
This is a talking stick.
小组里无论谁  只要拿着发言棒
Whoever's gonna be talking in the group
才能发言
will be carrying that stick.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
很好
Good.
很好吗
Good?
-你确定吗  -是的
- You're sure? - Yeah...
我很开心
I feel very happy.
好吧  但是
Okay, the thing is...
我不相信你的话
I don't believe you.
为了安全地带能起作用
And for Safe Place to work,
你们一定要对自己的情绪坦诚相待
you're gonna have to be really honest about how you're feeling.
给  你想看看情绪图示吗
Here... you wanna take a look at the feelings chart?
好吧
Okay.
我觉得很郁闷
I feel... very depressed.
-很好  -很好
- Good. - Good?
是你逼她这么说的  现在她感觉糟透了
You just made her say that... and now she feels crappy.
喂
Hey!
不好意思  你没有发言棒不能说话
Excuse me, you can't talk without the talking stick.
为什么  你也没有啊
Why? You don't have one.
那玩意不能限制我
Oh, doesn't apply to me.
我是小组协调员
I'm the group facilitator.
不  你不是
No... no, you're not.
-我不是吗  -不是
- I'm not? - No.
既然如此  我希望这里成为
With that being said, I want this place to be a place
你们可以畅所欲言的地方  但要遵守指导方针
where you all feel free to talk within the given guidelines.
不如这样
Tell you what...
我们换一换
let's switch.
-发言棒给你  -不
- Here, you take the stick. - No.
-拿着  -我没话说
- Come on. - I... I don't got nothing to say.
你肯定有  快告诉我们你现在的情绪
Sure you do. Just tell us how you're feeling.
无聊
Bored.
无聊不是一种情绪
Bored isn't a feeling.
这话什么意思  这不是情绪吗
What do you mean, it's not a feeling?
因为这不在情绪图示上
It's not on the feelings chart.
好
Fine!
生气  我感觉生气
Mad. I feel mad.
好的
Okay.
你为什么生气
And why do you feel mad?
因为你告诉我  我不能感觉无聊
'Cause you told me I couldn't feel bored!
抱歉
Sorry.
你迟到了
You're late.
我以为地点是在礼拜堂
I thought it was in the chapel.
随便坐
Take a seat.
华盛顿  你刚说什么
Okay, Washington, you were saying?
我什么也没有说
I wasn't saying anything.
这意义是什么
What is the point of this?
取消一次记过
To get a shot off your record.
不是
No...
意义是要帮助你们
the point is to help you
开始了解自己的情绪
to start to get in touch with your feelings.
你难道没有想过
Did it ever occur to you that
我们根本不想了解自己的情绪吗
we don't wanna get in touch with our feelings?
因为感受自己的情绪
That actually feeling our feelings
很可能会让我们无法在这生存
might make it impossible to survive in here?
听着
Look...
我试着去照看你
I'm trying to look out for you.
这里的每一个人  我们必须互相照看
Everybody in here, we have to look out for each other.
你看起来好像受伤了  怎么了
Now you look like you got hurt. What happened?
没事
Nothing happened.
-干嘛  -华盛顿
- What? - Washington...
你在这里说的话  不会被泄露出去的
what happens in Safe Place stays in Safe Place.
所以这里称为安全地带
That's why it's called Safe Place.
真的没事
Nothing happened.
我洗澡时摔了一跤
I slipped in the shower.
完全是意外
Totally random.
我们时间有限
We have a limited amount of time
压力必须来自外面
and the pressure needs to come from outside.
你已经跟谁说过这件事
Who have you already talked to about this?
我有两个激进分子的朋友帮我传达信息
I have some activist friends I told to get the word out.
-他们是谁  -特里和格斯
- Who are they? - Terry and Gus.
格斯是一个反伐木博客的网管
Gus is a webmaster for an anti-logging blog,
特里有一家蛋糕店  卖的都是反独裁的蛋糕
and Terry runs a bakery that sells anti-authoritarian cupcakes.
联系女修会领导会议
Contact the Leadership Conference of Women Religious,
还有国家天主教社会公正游说会
and the National Catholic Social Justice Lobby.
他们跟各大报纸都有联系
They can network with the major newspapers.
好吧  好吧  先等等
Okay... okay... back up.
我有话要说
I have to say something.
之前告诉我  我们的运动没有领袖
I was told this is a leaderless movement,
而现在你让我觉得不舒服
and I'm feeling uncomfortable
因为我觉得  你已经开始
with the fact that you're really...
像是我们的领导
I feel, acting like a leader.
因为我们都是有想法的人
Because we all got ideas...
可你是最后一个加入的人
but you were the last one to join up.
对  我也有这种感觉
Yeah, and I also feel that way.
抱歉我让你们觉得我
I'm sorry that you feel I've been...
像领导
leader-y.
每个人的想法都很重要
Everyone's ideas are important.
没关系
That's okay.
-问题解决  -我们原谅你了
- It's water under the creek. - We forgive you!
只要你知道
Long as you know...
要有人为我们所有人的利益而战
all our interests gots to be represented...
因为我和安琪想到几条新要求
'cause me and Angie got some new demands.
-我们要求增加甜点种类  -对
- We would like more dessert options. - Yeah!
还有出监狱的次数
And field trips.
要邀请音乐家来监狱  比如约翰尼・卡什
And musical guests in the prison, like Johnny Cash.
约翰尼・卡什死了
Johnny Cash is dead.
我就要
I want what I want.
天呐
Oh, boy!
你们肯定不会相信  我们点了太多披萨
You'll never believe this. We ordered too many pizzas.
谁想来一块啊
Anybody want a slice?
-这招真贱  -或许吧
- That's dirty warfare. - Uh, maybe...
但那可是一个好看又好吃的派
but that is one good-looking pie.
-琳恩  安琪  你们在干嘛  -没干嘛
- Leanne, Angie! What are you doing? - Nothing.
我们闻闻而已
We're smelling it.
我们只是闻闻  这么做是可以的
We're just smelling it. That's allowed.
闻起来的确很香  对吧
It sure does smell good, doesn't it?
小凯撒披萨哦
Little Caesars.
这比你们的要求更棒
It's the only thing better than getting what you want.
你们应该拿那句话来当口号
That should be their slogan.
坐牢已经是受罪了  我们何苦还要折磨自己呢
Why are we punishing ourselves when we're already being punished?
这样不合理
That makes no sense.
是啊  我们也可以说我们没吃  没人会知道
Yeah, we could still say we're not eating and nobody would know.
琳恩
Leanne...
你的贪欲是敌人  你一定要战胜它
your mind is the enemy. Don't listen to your mind...
-安琪  -我就舔一口
- Angie! - I'm just licking it.
舔一口又不会怎么样
A lick is all right.
-没关系  让她们吃吧  -什么
- It's all right. Let them eat. - What?
吃吧  姑娘们  暂时抛下你们的价值观
Go ahead, girls. Take a break from your values.
好的
I am.
那又是一句棒口号
That is another good slogan!
你为什么要这么做
What did you do that for?
我们不需要她们
We don't need them.
她们会混淆我们要表达的信息
They confuse our message.
她们是我们运动的一半人
They're half our movement!
你刚不是说每个人的想法都很重要吗
What happened to everyone's ideas being important?
-我改主意了  -瞧
- I changed my mind. - Hey, look.
我是爱德华披萨手
I'm Edward Pizzahands.
当他们逮捕我们时  我已经被逮捕过14次了
So when they arrest us... that's 14 arrests for me.
这比乔安修女还多两次
That's two more than Sister Joann,
比帕特丽夏修女多五次
and five more than Sister Patricia...
即使她在"地球之友"
even though she's the little
是人人喜爱的小可爱
darling over there at Friends of the Earth.
-这些都不重要  -这可是我的加分点
- That's not what's important. - It's a bonus.
不要核弹  住手吧
为流血国度悲戚
我们应该多带点条幅来
I guess we should've brought more banners.
就是  今天真不适宜干这个
I know. What a shitty day to do this.
话说有人在这里工作吗
I mean, does anybody work here?
有人吗
Hello!
我们非法入侵啦
We're trespassing!
吉恩  帮我拍照
Oh, Gene, take a picture.
那是什么
What's that?
帕特丽夏修女抗议朴茨茅斯一家工厂时
When Sister Patricia was protesting the Portsmouth Plant,
她泼了一品脱的血
she threw a pint of blood.
所以呢  你就带来一夸脱吗[相当于两品脱]
So what, you brought a quart?
是两夸脱
Two quarts.
假的  是道具血
Fake. Costume blood.
帕特丽夏修女泼的血
The blood that Sister Patricia threw
是真的来自辐射中毒的受害者
was from an actual victim of radiation poisoning.
照片效果一定很棒
The pictures will look spectacular!
干嘛
What?
我觉得你做这件事的心态不对
I don't think you're doing this in the right spirit.
你没资格跟我说心态
Don't talk to me about spirit.
没有我  你们俩不过是接受救济的嬉皮士
Without me, you're just a couple of hippies on welfare.
是我让别人信任你们  知道吗
I'm the one who gives you credibility, all right?
准备好了吗  吉恩
You're ready, Gene?
快拍
Get snapping.
-救命  -你们俩蠢货
- Help! - All right, pigs!
不许动  否则这贱人就要挨枪子了
Don't make another move or the bitch gets it!
你为什么要这么做
What did you do that for?
这是演习  就算有人质我们也不谈判
That's the drill. We don't negotiate for hostages.
所以你们就让她死吗
So you let me kill her?
是啊  开什么玩笑  奥尼尔
Yeah, seriously, O'Neill?
我很确定  我把枪撞掉了
Okay, I'm pretty sure... I knocked the gun away.
我也很确定她还活着
I'm pretty sure she's still alive.
不  我杀了她
No, I killed her.
我一枪打爆她的头
I shot her in the face.
子弹从她的左眼眶进去
The bullet entered the left eye socket
然后从后脑勺出来
and exited through the back of her head.
血和脑浆溅得到处都是
There's blood and brains everywhere.
沃森
Hey, Watson.
不是故意要吓你
Didn't mean to startle you.
只想告诉你  我很开心你回来了
Just wanted to say I'm happy you're back.
关于这一切  其实有件好事
You know, one good thing to come out of all this?
它促使我去参加绝食抗议
It... got me motivated to join the hunger strike.
你知道那件事吗
Do you know about that?
我一周都没吃过东西
I haven't eaten in a week.
那又怎么样
So what?
我应该感激你吗
Am I supposed to be grateful?
我不是来让你自我感觉良好的  好吗
I'm not here to make you feel good about yourself, all right?
你对某事内疚
You got guilt about something...
那不关我的事
that's not my problem.
不  不是你想的那样
No, it's not anything like that.
听着
Look...
我不想当你的黑人纪念品朋友
I don't feel like being your token black friend.
所以以后不要跟我说话了
So don't talk to me anymore.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
当然  宝贝  你想要什么我都可以搞到
Sure, baby... you know, I can get you anything you want.
因为在这里  我就像蜂王  你懂我意思吗
'Cause around here, I'm like King Bee, you know what I'm saying?
红妈
Hey, Red.
这个时候你不都跟园艺俱乐部的人玩吗
Aren't you usually playing with the garden club about now?
温室要暂时关闭了
The greenhouse is closed for a little while.
有个会危害健康的状况需要处理
There's a health hazard that needs to be sorted out.
是吗  是什么
Really? What?
一只老鼠[内鬼]
A rat.
这是干嘛
What the hell?
一边去  大奶妹
Hey, take a walk, bouncy boobs.
警告你们几个贱人  不许靠近我
All right, none of you bitches better come near me.
别紧张  我们不会伤害你
Relax, we're not going to hurt you.
给
Here.
这是你之前要的
You asked for these.
慢慢享用
Enjoy them.
因为这是我最后一次帮你
It'll be the last favor I ever do for you.
我被踢出家族了
I'm out of the family.
真遗憾
What a shame.
尤其是我们的关系
Especially since our relationship
是建立在高度的相互尊重之上
has always involved such a high degree of mutual respect.
你需要多一点关爱吗
You need more love?
我不用你假客套
I don't need shit.
谁稀罕你的水果硬糖
Fuck your Jolly Ranchers.
这里还有卖的糖果更好的地方
There are houses on this block with much better candy.
你宁愿去维的桌子上吃饭  是吗
You'd rather eat at Vee's table, would you?
是  那又怎样
Yeah... so what?
难道我就成了种族背叛者吗
Does that make me some kind of race betrayer?
拜托  你得了吧
I mean, give me a fucking break.
你带着你几个小喽来
You come down here with your scarecrows,
是想装黑帮吓唬我吗
trying to act all gangster?
她们所谓的忠诚是你用糖果和护肤品换来的
You buy loyalty with candy and skin care products.
你的黑帮看起来
I mean, your gang looks
像一群半价的垃圾桶屁孩
like a bunch of half-price Garbage Pail Kids...
红妈  你他妈就是个笑话
Red... you're a fucking joke.
你说得对
You're right.
我是个笑话
I'm a joke.
我敢说以后你自己会混得很好
I'm sure you'll be better off on your own.
我知道我一定会
I know I fucking will!
大波
Boo got Boo...
靠自己就够了
and that's all Boo needs.
大波
Boo.
该死的
Fuck.
要求囚犯权利
多谢你制作海报
Thank you for making those.
我应该帮忙的
I should help.
没关系  我来就行
It's okay, I got it.
你应该保留你的精力
You should conserve your energy.
皇后区
Queens, huh?
我应该介绍她给我的好友米歇尔认识
I should hook her up with my buddy, Michel.
他在皇后大桥下面开了一家脱衣舞俱乐部
He runs a strip joint underneath the Queensboro Bridge.
脱光光那种哦  但那里不提供酒精饮品
Well, it's full nude, but they don't serve alcohol.
这状况真是太糟了
It's just such a fucked situation.
我知道  但这就是法律
I know, man, that's the law.
我猜某个蠢蛋觉得裸体和酒精
'Cause I... I guess some schmuck decided that
两者同时享受太过欢乐了
nudity and booze at the same time's just too much fun.
估计是一个有六个老婆的摩门教徒
It's probably a Mormon with six wives.
我是说艾丽克斯
I'm talking about Alex.
她应该受到证人保护
She should be under witness protection.
你关心她干嘛
What do you care?
话说在芝加哥的时候  不是她耍了你吗
I mean, didn't she screw you over in Chicago?
对哦
Oh, that's right.
你们俩的关系就是这样  不是吗
That's kind of how you two relate, isn't it?
就像间谍大战  只不过性方面的
It's like Spy vs. Spy, but sexual.
你要知道库巴这个家伙  不是闹着玩的
You know something, this guy, Kubra, he's no joke...
他们也知道
and they know that.
他们把她置于险境
They're not taking responsibility
却毫不承担责任
for the fact that they put her in harm's way.
如果这不是协议的一部分  那他们就不管
If it's not part of your deal, it's just not part of your deal.
政府的人没有良心
Yeah, the system doesn't have a conscience
而且没人喜欢多干事
and nobody likes extra work.
对了
Oh, by the way...
我们电工这周要帮忙
we're gonna be helping to put sandbags
把沙袋堆到湖周围
around the lake in electrical this week.
什么  这跟电有什么关系
What? What does that have to do with electrical?
万一在风暴时  湖水泛滥
If the lake overflows during the storm,
我们都会被电死
then we all get electrocuted.
我不知道
I don't know.
这里有没什么专门搬沙袋的部门
It's not like there's a sandbag department.
警员  把这些马克笔  纸张还有海报统统没收
Officer, confiscate those markers, paper, posters, all of it.
但这是美术用品
But these are just art supplies.
它们被人滥用来干别的事
They are a privilege that has been abused.
这不是滥用  这是权利
It's not a privilege. It's a right!
慢点  修女  别站起来太快
Careful, Sister, don't stand up too fast.
我们有言论自由
We have freedom of speech.
你之前有  但你后来犯法了
You did and then you broke the law.
你以为你现在在哪里
Where do you think you are?
还有这个  给我停止
And as for this... no more.
这个表达自由  想把监狱变成华尔道夫酒店的
This little experiment in free expression,
小实验已经结束了
Waldorf-style prison... is over.
贱妇
Fucking cunt.
你犯不着这样
You didn't need to do that.
你激怒了她们  她们会更来劲
You let 'em get a rise out of you, gives them more power.
你被人欺负的时候  你妈妈就这样教你的吗
Oh, is that what your mommy told you when you were being bullied?
绝食抗议  开什么玩笑
A hunger strike, really?
那我该怎么办  强迫喂她们吃吗
What should I be doing, force-feeding them?
-有何不可  -因为我不能
- Why not? - Because I can't.
除非她们失去意识
Unless they're unconscious.
我才能这样做  还得她们没签"无需抢救"书
Then I can do it if they don't have a DNR.
那好  那就试着在她们睡觉时这么干
Fine, then try and get them while they're sleeping.
我们有责任
We have a responsibility
喂这些女囚一天三顿饭
to feed these women three square meals a day,
而我是一个女性权益捍卫者
and I am a defender of women.
还有其他事需要我做吗  长官
Do you want me to do anything else, sir?
不用了
It's all right.
她们最后肯定会受不了的
It's gonna play itself out.
丢脸
An embarrassment?
这应该是成就
It should be a triumph.
我上了《纽约时代》的封面
I... I was on the cover of The New York Times.
你看问题就在这
You see, that is exactly the issue.
这事无关侍奉主  是关于你
It's not about service to God... it's about you.
你是个自恋狂
You're a narcissist.
才不是
That's not true.
不是吗
No?
修女要过去
你这次抗议的时间正好跟你书的发行时间一致
You timed this protest to coincide with your book release...
而且你都没给你的代笔者署名
and you didn't even credit your ghostwriter.
我把所有的收益都捐给慈善机构了  这是上帝的旨意
I'm giving all the proceeds to charity. I'm doing God's work.
你知道这代表什么吗
Hey... you know what this stands for?
第二次梵蒂冈会议
Vatican II.
你当修女不开心吗
Are you not happy being a nun?
不啊
No!
我非常喜欢当修女
I love being a nun.
如果我看起来太自傲  那是因为我太爱这份工作
If I seem prideful, it's only because I love the work I do...
同时也因为我太擅长这份工作
and because I'm really good at it.
那是你自己这么认为
By your own estimation.
你书上有一页我想给你念念
There is a page in your book I'd like to read for you.
"我从未在心里清楚地听到耶稣的声音
"I have never heard Christ clearly in my heart.
要么是我的心听力不好
Either my heart's hard of hearing,
要么就是耶稣有点口齿不清
or Christ can be a bit of a mumbler...
于是我学着去信任自己的道德直觉"
And so I've learned to trust in my own moral instincts."
这是个玩笑
It's a joke.
我只是拿我和耶稣的婚姻
I'm comparing my marriage to Christ...
跟普通的婚姻对比
to a typical marriage.
"但并不是我的道德直觉
"But it wasn't my moral instincts
促使我在1988年夏天去尼加拉瓜
that led me to Nicaragua in the summer of '88.
而是一位名叫卡洛斯的年轻自由战士..."
It was a young freedom fighter named Carlos."
好吧
Okay...
"他的丛林装下有着岩石般坚硬的腹肌
"With rock-hard abs under his jungle fatigues...
卡洛斯不只是一个方面的革新者
Carlos was revolutionary in more ways than one...
推翻桑地诺也不是他的唯一目标"
And overthrowing the Sandinistas was not his only objective."
好吧  那一章是专门写给妈妈书友会的粉丝
Okay, now, that chapter's there for the mommy book-club crowd.
她们读政治需要点猛男相伴
They need a little beefcake with their politics.
抱歉  修女
I'm sorry, Sister,
但教堂决定我们不会再支持你了
but the church has decided we can't support you any longer.
支持我
Support me?
你是说
You mean...
你们不会再为我付律师费吗
you won't pay my legal fees?
我是说我们不能再支持你了
I mean we can't support you...
就是这样
period.
你说她不来了是什么意思
What do you mean, she's not coming?
她说她不想再干了
She said she doesn't wanna do it anymore.
以后也不会给我们私货了
And no more contraband either.
但我们才开始
But we just started.
是因为那个黑人吗
Is this about the black one?
什么  去你的
What? Fuck you!
不是你  你不是那些坏黑人
Not you. You're not one of the bad ones.
她是说维
She means Vee.
红妈宁愿撤掉隧道  也不让她接手
Red would rather kill the tunnel than let her take it.
那个头发很多的  我知道她
That's the one with the big hair. I know her.
但我喜欢接触土壤
But I love being in touch with the soil.
我知道
I know.
这个俱乐部是
This club is the best thing
我不用干活后最棒的事情
that's happened to me since work exemption.
或许红妈没有想清楚
Well, maybe Red isn't thinking straight.
当海盗上船时
When the pirates are boarding,
我们不是要把船弄沉  而是奋起反抗
you don't sink the ship, you fight the damn pirates.
再说一遍
Say again?
不如我把那个贱货杀了
How 'bout I kill the bitch?
然后我们玩一个叫手结的游戏  我们双手握住
Then we played a game called Human Knot where we all held hands
试图在不松开手的情况下解开结
and tried to unknot the knot without letting go.
弗洛雷斯  她
And Flores... she got...
不小心挠到自己  就开始在那笑
accidentally got tickled and started laughing
于是我们大家都开始笑  那真是...
and then we all started laughing and it was so...
听起来超基
Sounds mad gay.
是啊  的确超级基
Yeah, it was mad gay.
你们在说什么
Yo, what y'all talking about?
她去海利办的新活动上监视珀比
She went to keep an eye on Poussey in Healy's thing.
你不需要那样做
You didn't have to do that.
我说过  她不会告密的
I told you, she ain't no fink.
你是说过  但是你知道吗
You said that. But you know what?
我不是很确定你现在究竟忠诚于谁
I'm not really sure where your loyalties lie these days.
你觉得呢  苏珊娜
What do you think, Suzanne?
我觉得她不会说的
Well, I don't think she's gonna talk,
但是她的组诗
but... I was a little disturbed by
让我有些分心
her contribution to the group poem.
诗里有很多愤怒和恐惧
It's a lot of anger. It's a lot of fear.
有你在那待着  当然会有啊
Well, of course there was with you right there.
吸血鬼都会被你吓到
You would spook a vampire.
如果你当初让我去  会好很多
If you would've had me go, it would've been better.
如果那么多如果和但是化成糖果和坚果
And if ifs and buts were candies and nuts,
那我们就能过个快乐圣诞节了
we'd all have a merry Christmas.
如果告密者和贱人是美酒和啤酒
And if snitches and bitches were wine and beer...
我们就能好好过个新年了  我说得对吗
we'd all have a happy New Year. Am I right?
如果愿望是马匹  乞丐人人都有马骑
If wishes were horses, beggars would ride.
为什么你要胳膊往外拐呢
Why do you keep defending her over your family?
我没有
I'm not.
我只是觉得她已经受够了
I... I just think she's been through enough.
但你真的不必担心她  维
But you don't have to worry about her, Vee, for real.
好  我不担心
Fine, I don't worry.
从今天开始  她归你管
But from now on, she's your responsibility.
如果再发生点什么事
Anything happens again...
就算在你头上
it's on you.
发生什么事了
What happened?
她晕倒了
She fainted.
就一下而已
For a second.
我还没失去意识
I'm not unconscious.
修女  我跟你的小团体谈过了
Sister, I talked to your compatriots.
我们已经做出了决定
I think there's been a decision made.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你放弃了
You gave up.
这行为现在太危险了  尤其对你而言
It's just not safe anymore... especially for you.
那是借口
That's an excuse.
你联系我之前说的媒体了吗
Did you contact the media like I asked you?
我试了
I tried.
没人愿意报道这件事
Nobody took the bait with the story.
风暴要来了
There's a storm coming.
你说得没错  风暴是要来了
You're damn right there's a storm coming.
不  我不是打比方
No, I don't mean it that way.
是真的有场大暴风雪  现在新闻都在报道这个
There's actually a big winter storm that's dominating all the news.
只是我们时机不对
It's just bad timing.
慢着  她是修女
Wait a minute. Sister's a nun.
你告诉我这个故事没有爆点吗
You're telling me that's not a story?
是啊  在她被逐出教会之前  她的确是修女
Yeah, it's less of one since she's been excommunicated.
称号而已
Labels.
他们告诉我
They told me that...
如果我在监狱里显示出悔悟
they'd reconsider letting me back in the church
他们会重新考虑让我回教会  但
if I showed contrition in prison, but...
坏习惯很难改
bad habits die hard.
坏习惯  懂吗
Bad habits. Get it?
重新上位掌权的感觉真好
It's good to be back in the saddle.
是啊  除非你放弃你的位子
Yeah, well, unless you get out of the saddle...
否则你就要坐着它直接进医疗隔离室了
you're gonna be riding straight into medical seg...
我可不想这种事发生
and I don't wanna have to do that.
所以就到此为止吧
So let's call it a day, huh?
除非你对这座监狱的
I'll call it a day...
运营方式作出有效的改革  我才会到此为止
when you make meaningful changes to the way this prison is run.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你没听到她说什么吗
Didn't you hear what she said?
这么做没有意义
There's no point.
你是孤军奋战
You're all alone.
根本没人知道你在这里的壮举
Nobody even knows you're doing this.
你知道
You know.
好吧
All right.
那随便你吧
Have it your way.
她来了
Here she comes!
拜托  修女  别这样对自己
Please, Sister, don't do this to yourself.
我没事  索菲娅
I'm fine, Sophia.
我感觉良好
I feel good.
非常幸福
Almost blissful.
她精神错乱了
She's delirious.
-加油  修女  -你真行
- Rock on, Sister. - You're all right.
对抗权势
Fight the power.
她觉得自己是摇滚明星
She thinks she's a rock star.
她就是
She is.
不是应该谦卑吗
Whatever happened to humility?
难道那不是美德什么的吗
Isn't that a virtue or something?
最大的美德之一
One of the highest.
当权者经常这么说
People in power are always saying so.
海利先生  你听说简报的事了吗
Mr. Healy, did you hear about the Bugle?
我无能为力
I can't do anything about it.
但那很棒
But it was so good.
真的
It really was.
人们开始承担责任  敞开心扉
People were taking responsibility. People were opening up.
这都是你希望看见的呀
It's everything that you wanted to see happen.
-查普曼  -我是说  作为辅导员
- Chapman... - I mean, as a... as a counselor...
你要被转移去
You're being transferred...
弗吉尼亚
to Virginia.
什么
What?
典狱长办公室给我发来备忘录
I received a memo from the warden's office.
你和其他12名女囚的名字都在上面
Yeah, your name was included on a list with 12 other girls.
是因为简报吗
Is this because of the paper?
是因为我刊登了绝食抗议的要求
Is this because I published the strike demands?
是菲格吗
Is this Fig?
这不是惩罚你
It's not punitive.
我们经常来回转移犯人
We shuffle prisoners around all the time.
这里人太多了
We're overpopulated.
你在名单上
The fact that you're on a list...
是完全随机选中的
it's... just a random thing.
什么时候走
When?
或许是一周内
Maybe in a week.
他们通常会周六来接犯人
They usually pick 'em up on Saturday.
那是探监日
No, that's visitation day.
艾丽克斯会来看我
Alex was gonna come visit me.
她能不能来要当天才能知道
I don't know if she can come before then.
她说她需要当面跟我谈谈
She said that she needs to speak with me in person.
查普曼  你要南下了
Chapman... you're going down south.
你和艾丽克斯・沃斯的问题没解决
Not having closure with Alex Vause...
是你最不应该关心的问题
would be the least of your problems.
还要多久
How much longer? How much...
这么大的噪音还要持续多久
how much longer with this level of noise?
可能还有几个小时
Probably a few hours.
好吧  只要能把活干完
All right, as long as it gets done.
一定干好
It'll get done.
B区的厕所在修了
I see B-Dorm bathroom is being fixed.
没错
That's right.
事情的发展有时就是让人想不到
Funny how things work out sometimes.
维
Yo, Vee!
我已经不跟红妈了  所以我是你的人了
I'm not with Red anymore, so I'm... all yours.
-我的人  -是啊
- Mine? - Yeah.
但我为什么会要你
But why would I want you?
我帮过你  给你爆过料
I did right by you, Vee. I gave you the 411.
我不喜欢告密者
I don't like snitches.
为什么你总是那么安静
Why are you always so quiet?
为什么总是让我自言自语
Why do I always have to do all the talking?
安歇于主
Oh, rest in the Lord
耐心等候k
Wait patiently for Him
我做错了什么
What the... fuck did I do?
我做了什么
What did I do?
我还没昏迷
I'm awake.
I'm awake. I'm awake!
我还没昏迷
I'm awake!
我还醒着
不  不许喂我
No, don't feed me!
我不允许你们这么做
I did not give my permission!
这么做是错的  这不公平
This is not right! It's not fair!
不  住手  快住手
No, please! Please!